JAMES IMODOI EPALE

Nairobi, Kenya · +254743854888

Email: Ijepale@gmail.com · LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamesepale/

GitHub Projects: https://github.com/imodoiepale

I am a passionate IT specialist and Software Developer with 2 years of Experience and with the enforcement of quick critical thinking, and logical technical skills to improve my work efficiency. My combination of experience, computer skills, and a proven diligent work ethic gets the job done.

SKILLS

- Web development: HTML, CSS, React, Node.js, WordPress, Elementor
- Programming languages: Java, Python, C++, JavaScript
- Software development methodologies: Agile, Waterfall
- Software development tools: Visual Studio, Git, Figma
- Database management: MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Team Development tools: Jira, Trello
- Cloud computing: AWS, Google's Firebase
- Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Publisher
- Proficient in the use of computer systems, networks, and software applications
- Experienced in the installation, configuration, and maintenance of computer hardware and software
- Skilled in troubleshooting and problem-solving
- Strong problem-solving and analytical skills
- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills

EXPERIENCE

APRIL 2022 - PRESENT

WEB DEVELOPER, WEB AGE TECHNOLOGIES, NAIROBI

- Designed and developed software solutions using Java and Python
- Developed Websites using WordPress
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure the successful delivery of software projects
- Participated in code reviews and testing to ensure the quality of software products
- Maintained and updated existing software applications
- Implemented and maintained software documentation
- Successfully identified, diagnosed, and fixed website problems, including broken links, typographical errors, and formatting issues.
- Managed front-end and back-end development in the company
- Interfaced with clients to identify business requirements.
- Building consistent looking and visual-themed websites according to client specifications

APRIL 2020 - PRESENT

FREELANCE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, NAIROBI

- Successfully completed over 30 Custom Website Design jobs with a strong customer satisfaction rate
- Managed front-end and back-end development for a school website
- Interfaced with clients to identify business requirements.
- Worked to assess competing websites regarding content, look, and feel
- Teaching and tutoring on Web Development
- Installed, configured, and maintained computer systems and networks

- Provided technical support to end-users and resolved hardware and software issues
- Implemented and managed network security protocols and procedures
- Conducted regular system backups and disaster recovery testing
- Developed and implemented IT policies and procedures to ensure the optimal functioning of computer systems and networks

EDUCATION

SEP 2021 - PRESENT

BSC. SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT, KCA UNIVERSITY

- Short overview of projects and assignments some available on my GitHub
- Technical Stack overview: Java, C++, VB.NET, Python

JAN 2017 - APR 2021

KCSE, STAREHE BOYS' CENTRE AND SCHOOL

KCSE GRADE: A-

PROJECTS

GitHub Projects: https://github.com/imodoiepale

Website: https://imodoiepale.vercel.app

REFEREES

David Kipkemboi Kelvin Murage

Email: davidkla12@gmail.com Email: kevinmurage@gmail.com